Summary

Front-End Engineer (tech lead, architect) with 6 years of proven leadership experience and meaningful contributions to teams of varying sizes working with Vue and React and integration with back-end APIs.

Skills

Expert: HTML5, CSS, SASS, ES6, Git, JavaScript, Jest, NPM, Yarn, React, Redux, Vue, Vuex, Bootstrap, SQL, 508 Compliance, Scrum, Azure DevOps, TFS, Spanish.

Intermediate: Node, Typescript, Node, Express, Webpack, Angular, C#, .NET Core, .NET Framework, Web Forms.

Work Experience

<u>Senior Software Engineer</u> Navient, Fishers, IN

Dec 2021 - Current

- Led development of web application components and interfaces utilizing Vue and React.
- Worked across different teams to train on how effectively use a JavaScript framework (Vue and React).
- Led efforts in training teams in Agile practices and ensuring applications were developed with proper architecture.
- Gave tech talks across IT to provide awareness about the latest technology by talking about enterprisewide solutions to assist teams.
- Led Scrum ceremonies to ensure the team worked effectively by using strategies to increase efficiency.

<u>Software Engineer II</u> Navient, Fishers, IN

Dec 2019 – Sep 2021

- Led efforts implementing React web applications by using reusable UI components, mobile-first, and Redux flow as a model layer for the components.
- Mentored junior developers and interns on the team by expanding JavaScript and React skillset.
- Integrated WhiteSource to view and resolve vulnerabilities in applications.

<u>Software Engineer I</u> Navient, Fishers, IN

Dec 2017 – Dec 2019

- Handled front-end development and architecture to create a multi-tenant servicing platform.
- Administered code reviews and merge requests to deliver updates to the repository codebase.
- Rewrote HTML and JavaScript to meet industry and company standards for 508 Compliance.

Software Engineer (Intern) Navient, Fishers, IN

June 2016 - Dec 2017

- Automated dashboard using C#, SQL, SharePoint, and Power BI.
- Front-end developing using Bootstrap 4, SASS, Angular 2, HTML 5, JQuery, .NET.
- Created a UX style guide for the company's website using Angular 2.

Projects

- <u>COVID-19 Portal</u> Provided over 1 million users with a portal where they can search and view their COVID-19 lab results.
- <u>Parking Alerts</u> Used React, Twilio, and .Net Core to allow 18,000 users to sign up and receive parking alerts.
- Get Next Recipient of Q3 2021 award for leading efforts in developing a web application to satisfy critical business needs in 2 days.
- <u>Customer Loan Dashboard</u> Worked on defects and provided critical functionality for over 16 million users using JavaScript, SCSS, and .Net Framework.
- HCServiclean Created for the company to provide information for clients that seek residential cleaning.

Education

Indiana University Purdue University